Logan family papers LCP.Logan
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series II. Algernon Sydney Logan papers, 1869-1925
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream", 1899-1901; [Yi2 1645 F 10] (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream", 1901-1905; [Yi2 1645 F 11] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream", 1905-1910; [Yi2 1645 F 12] (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream", 1911-1913; [Yi2 1645 F 13] (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream", 1913-1916; [Yi2 1645 F 14] (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream", 1916-1917; [Yi2 1645 F 15] (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream", 1917-1918; [Yi2 1645 F 16] (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream", 1918-1921; [Yi2 1645 F 17] (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - [Diary?] "Glimpse of Vistas from the Stream'; perhaps better 'Vistas from the Stream: An Autobiography of Impressions", 1921-1925; [Yi2 1645 F 19] (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Series III. Deborah Norris Logan papers
  - Diary with Norris and Logan family history, 1808-1814; [Yi2 14720 Q] (Volume 1)
  - "Memoir of James Logan" copy written originally for "Selections from his Correspondence", circa 1820; [Yi2 14722 Q] (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Biographical Sketch of the Life and Character of Doctor George Logan", 1821; [Yi2 1275] (Volume 2)
  - Biographical sketch of George Logan, fragment, [1821]; [Yi2 107124 O] (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Diary, three fascicles, 1838 November 11-December 4; [Yi2 107122 0] (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Obituary of Deborah Norris Logan, written by [Maria Dickinson Logan], 1839; [14721 Q] (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Frances Armat Logan collection
  - Warrant to C. Marshall and Company, 1684 December 19; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Receipts from Charles Marshall, 1684 November 28, 1685 March 19; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Statement concerning Mary Norris, 1694 October 5; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Elizabeth Webb, 1698 April 13, 1698 August 7, 1702 September 13; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Captain J. Cook, 1709 September 10; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Elizabeth Webb and A.W. Boehm, 1712 January 2; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Copy of letter written by Elizabeth Webb to her children, 1724 June 25; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Wedding announcement of Mary Cadwallader and Samuel Dickinson at the Friends Meeting in Philadelphia, 1731 November 28 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Letters from E. Wright, 1730 October 24-1735 April 25; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Letter from H. Dickinson, 1749 July 31; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Petition by John Baptiste Galerm, 1755; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Elegy, written at Sea (to Delia), 1762 August; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Death notices of Isaac Norris, Isaac, 1735 June 5, 1766 July 17; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - William Logan surgeon's certificate, 1771 January 24; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Frances Dodsham, 1774 December 27; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Deed by J. Lukens, 1775 August 19; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Diary, 1775 August 6-September 17; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - "To the Banished Society of Winchester" meeting, 1777; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Letter from P. Dickinson, 1777 January 22; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Letter of John Lloyd, 1777 May 1; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Debtor of John Dickinson, 1777 March- May 27; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Indenture for land of Caesar Rodney to John Dickinson, 1778 November 20-21; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Letter from M. Dickinson, 1779 March 23; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Death notice for Elizabeth Norris, 1779 July 6; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Letter from William Molleston, 1781 August 11; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Letter from S.P. Griffitts, 1781 October 1; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Letter from Thomas Rodney, 1785 June 4, 1784 November 13; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Account of Dorcas Lilly, 1786 January 25; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Receipt from the Library Company of Philadelphia, 1786 May 9; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Account of a dream written by John Dickinson, 1787; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Letter from James Logan, Jr., 1788 October 12; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Letter from Deborah Logan regarding George Logan, 1793 April 4; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Letter from J. Jenkins to Joseph Norris, 1793 April 4; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Yearly Meeting of Women's Friends, London, England, 1793 May 20; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Poem by Rebecca Archie, 1795 November; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Memo of Samuel Dickinson's marriage, 1798 December 17; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Will of Mary Parker Norris, 1799 January 24; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Letter from [L.] White, 1802 February 22; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Marriage certificate of Jacob Armstrong and Ann Jackson, Ann, 1803 February 24; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Letter from Gideon Gardner to George Logan, 1806 March 3; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Letter from George W. P. Custis to unidentified Logan, 1809 January 21; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Letter from Samuel Emlen to Sally Norris Dickinson, 1809 January 21; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Letter from James Vaux to Sally Norris Dickinson, 1808 May 10, 1809 August 17; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Testimony of New Garden Monthly Meeting respecting Ruth Anna Lindley, 1811 January 10; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Ode to Alexander of Russia, 1814; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Letter from Deborah Logan Norris, 1814 August 10; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Account of Thomas Clarkson, conference with the Emperor of Russia written by George Logan, 1816 July 11; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Letter from Richard M. Smith to Albanus Logan, 1816 October 11; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Verses by J. P., 1814-1817; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Letter from Margaret Hill Smith to George Logan, 1820 June 27; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Letter from John Fanning Watson to Deborah Logan, 1827 January 5; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Letter from Deborah Logan, 1827 March 14; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Certificate of lifetime membership to House of Refuge for Sally N. Dickinson, 1829 July 4; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Letter from J. A. Cox to Sally N. Dickinson, 1831 August 23; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Letter from Deborah Logan to Maria Logan, 1838 August 23; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Letter from Mary Jones, 1838 September 25; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - "The Hero of Niagara" poem by Mary Norris Logan, 1839 August 3; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - "To My Grandfather on his Ninetieth Birthday" poem by S. Parrish, 1844 February 23; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Letter from E. [Suerz], to Sally Norris Dickinson, 1854 March 13; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Visiting cards and invitations, undated; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Letter containing verse from S. Wright to Polly Norris, undated; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Letter from Eliza Priestley to William Logan, undated; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Letter from George Logan to Albanus Logan, undated; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Letter from Sarah Logan Fisher to Dr. Logan (brother), undated; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Letter from Deborah Logan, undated; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Verses by John Boyd, undated; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Autographs of Logan family and Dickinson family, undated; [Yi2 7421] (Box 9, Folder 67)
- Series V. James Logan papers
  - "A Genealogical Table of the Descendants of James Logan" by James Logan, circa 1867; [Yi2 5354] (Volume 3)
  - Commonplace book, circa 1730; [Yi2 577 F] (Volume 4)
  - "Account of land titles belonging to James Logan as kept by himself," by James Logan, circa 1730; [Yi2 1417 F] (Volume 5)
- Series VI. William Logan, Jr. papers
  - "Barton's Material Medica," manuscript copy, circa 1769; [Yi2 1617 Q] (Volume 6)
  - "Black's Chemistry," William Logan, Jr.'s notes on Joseph Black's chemistry lectures, circa 1770; [Yi2 1603 Q] (Volume 7)
  - "Black's Chemistry," William Logan, Jr.'s notes on Joseph Black's chemistry lectures, circa 1770; [Yi2 1603 Q] (Volume 8)
  - "Black's Chemistry," William Logan, Jr.'s notes on Joseph Black's chemistry lectures, circa 1770; [Yi2 1603 Q] (Volume 9)
  - "Blair's Rhetoric: A Course of Lectures on Rhetoric and Belle's Lettres by Hugh Blair D.D., Volume I", undated; [L-16, v. I 3468 D] (Volume 10)
  - "Blair's Rhetoric: A Course of Lectures on Rhetoric and Belle's Lettres by Hugh Blair D.D., Volume II", undated; [L-16, v. II 3468 D] (Volume 11)
  - "Boorhave: Commentaria in Librum Suum, C.P.H. Boerhaave commentaris in librum suum de cognoscendis et curandis morbis" by William Logan of Bristol, England, 1707-1714; [In3 488 Q] (Volume 12)
  - "Boorhave: Praelectiones Chemicae," Praelectiones Chemicae a C. P. Boorhave habita ad dirigendum studij medicina instituta," by William Logan of Bristol, England, Volume I, 1710; [Lk4 296 Q Log] (Volume 13)
  - "Boorhave: Praelectiones Chemicae," Praelectiones Chemicae a C. P. Boorhave habita ad dirigendum studij medicina instituta," by William Logan of Bristol, England, Volume II, 1710; [Lk4 296 Q Log] (Volume 14)
  - "Boorhave: Praelectiones Chemicae a C.P.D. boor have habita de actionibus medicamentorum;" by William Logan of Bristol, England, 1710 November 10; [In2 289 Q Log] (Volume 15)
  - Cullen, William: Lectures on medicine and notes on Dr. Joseph Black's lectures on chemistry, 1760; [In3 3478 D] (Volume 16)
  - "Cullen's Chemistry Lectures", 1763 October 21-1764 March 23; [Yi2 1605 Q] (Volume 17)
  - Cullen, William: "Pathologia Culloni: Pathology Delivered by Dr. Cullen, Volume I", 1766 (Volume 18)
  - Cullen, William: "Pathologia Culloni: Pathology Delivered by Dr. Cullen, Volume II", 1767 (Volume 19)
  - "Cullen's Phisiology: Introduction to Doctor Cullen's Phisiological Lectures, Volume I", 1769; [In1 1606 Q Logan] (Volume 20)
  - "Cullen's Phisiology: Introduction to Doctor Cullen's Phisiological Lectures, Volume II", 1769; [In1 1606 Q Logan] (Volume 21)
  - "Cullen's Phisiology: Introduction to Doctor Cullen's Phisiological Lectures, Volume III", 1769; [In1 1606 Q Logan] (Volume 22)
  - "Cullen's Phisiology: Introduction to Doctor Cullen's Phisiological Lectures, Volume IV", 1769; [In1 1606 Q Logan] (Volume 23)
  - "William Cullen Clinical Lectures," manuscript notes of lectures delivered at Canongate, 1770; [In3 3284 D] (Volume 24)
  - "Duncan's Therapeutical Lectures", 1770; [In3 3383 D Log] (Volume 25)
  - "Gregory Lecture: Course of Lectures on Physic by John Gregory, MD., Volume I", 1768; [In3 1608 Q Log] (Volume 26)
  - "Gregory Lecture: Course of Lectures on Physic by John Gregory, MD., Volume II", 1768; [In3 1608 Q Log] (Volume 27)
  - "Gregory Lecture: Course of Lectures on Physic by John Gregory, MD., Volume III", 1768; [In3 1608 Q Log] (Volume 28)
  - "Gregory Lecture: Course of Lectures on Physic by John Gregory, MD., Volume IV", 1768; [In3 1608 Q Log] (Volume 29)
  - "Gregory's Practice, Volume I", circa 1769; [In3 1609 Q] (Volume 30)
  - "Gregory's Practice, Volume II", circa 1769; [In3 1609 Q] (Volume 31)
  - "Gregory's Physiology Institutions of Medicine; Lectures on Botany", circa 1769 (Volume 32)
  - "Gregory's Clinical Lectures", circa 1770; [In3 3466 D Log] (Volume 33)
  - Home, Francis: "Clinical Lectures and Medical Cases", 1769; [In3 1613 Q Log] (Volume 34)
  - [Leyoelt?, Gabriell P.] "Speeches in the House of Commons", 1640; [Yi2 613 Q] (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "French observations on making Indico at Cape-Francois also Thomas Mellichamps method of making Flora Indico in South Carolina," manuscript notes, circa 1757 (Volume 35)
  - Logan, William Jr.:"Clinical lectures attempted after the manner of Doctor Cullen, Professor of Phisiology", 1768; [In3 1612 Q] (Volume 36)
  - Logan, William Jr.: "Chemical Lectures: Lectures on Chemistry Attempted After the Manner of the Learned and Truly Ingenious Doctor Black, Professor of Chemistry in the University of Edinburg, Volume I", 1768 November 7; [Yi2 1607 Q] (Volume 37)
  - Logan, William Jr.: "Chemical Lectures: Lectures on Chemistry Attempted After the Manner of the Learned and Truly Ingenious Doctor Black, Professor of Chemistry in the University of Edinburg, Volume II", 1769 November 7; [Yi2 1607 Q] (Volume 38)
  - Logan, William, Jr. "Infirmary Clinical Cases 1769," manuscript notes, [In3 1615 Q Log] (Volume 39)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Medical and Philosophical Papers read before the Physico: Medical Society of Edinburgh", 1769; [In3 3320 D] (Volume 40)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: Medical observations and notes, circa 1769 (Volume 41)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Materia Medica," manuscript notes, circa 1769; [In 1501 F] (Volume 42)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Practice of Medicines," manuscript notes, circa 1769; [In3 1502 F] (Volume 43)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: Medical practice cases, circa 1770 (Volume 44)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "De Fermentation," student notes, circa 1770 (Volume 45)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Breviuscula Synopsis Neumatogiae", circa 1770; [Yi2 No. 702] (Volume 46)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Commentarius in Aristotelis Philosphiam", circa 1770; [Yi2 No. 997 Q] (Volume 47)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Commentarius in Aristotelem", circa 1770; [Yi2 No. 998 Q] (Volume 48)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Breviae in Universa Philosphiam", circa 1770; [Yi2 No. 999 Q] (Volume 49)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Commentarius in Aristotelis Physican, Volume I", circa 1770; [Yi2 No. 1000 Q] (Volume 50)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Commentarius in Aristotelis Physican, Volume II", circa 1770; [Yi2 No. 1000 Q] (Volume 51)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Commentarius in Aristotelis Physican, Volume III", circa 1770; [Yi2 No. 1000 Q] (Volume 52)
  - Logan, William, Jr.: "Arnold of Brescia, Rienzi Savonaro la, Ximenes, Fra Paolo," quotes and biographical memoirs, circa 1770; [Yi2 1391 Q] (Volume 53)
  - [Logan, William, Jr.?]: "An Ironical Panegyrick on Drunkenness", 18th century; [Log 918 Q 5] (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - "Monro, Alexander: Lectures on Anatomy, Volume I", circa 1770; [In1 1604 Q] (Volume 54)
  - "Monro, Alexander: Lectures on Anatomy, Volume II", circa 1770; [In1 1604 Q] (Volume 55)
  - "Monro, Alexander: Lectures on Anatomy, Volume III", circa 1770; [In1 1604 Q] (Volume 56)
  - "Monro, Alexander: Lectures on Surgery and the Practice of Medicine, Volume I", 1768; [In3 1610 Q] (Volume 57)
  - "Monro, Alexander: Lectures on Surgery and the Practice of Medicine, Volume II", 1768; [In3 1610 Q] (Volume 58)
  - "Monro, Alexander: Lectures on Surgery and the Practice of Medicine, Volume II", 1768; [In3 1610 Q] (Volume 59)
  - "Monro, Alexander: Lectures on Surgery and the Practice of Medicine, Volume IV", 1768; [In3 1610 Q] (Volume 60)
  - Young, Thomas: "History of Fevers," manuscript notes taken by William Logan, Jr. at lecture by Thomas Young, 1768; [In5 1614 D Log] (Volume 61)
  - "Young's Midwifery," manuscript notes taken by William Logan, Jr. at lecture by Thomas Young, 1769; [In4 1616 Q Log] (Volume 62)
- Series VII. William Logan Fox collection of papers relating to the Library Company of Philadelphia v. William Logan Estate
  - Letter from Thomas Fisher to Library Company of Philadelphia, 1794 June 2; [Yi2 1438 F 1] (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Thomas Fisher to Library Company of Philadelphia, 1794 June 2; [Yi2 1438 F 2] (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Accounts of Library Company with William Logan, 1753-1759; [Yi2 1438 F 3] (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Sundry tenants accounts on the Loganian Library lands in Solebury, Bucks County, 1753-1760; [Yi2 1438 F 4] (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Accounts of William Logan of the Loganian Library, 1760-1778; [Yi2 1438 F 5] (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Edward Tilghman and William Lewis opinion on deed, 1795 August 10; [Yi2 1438 F 6] (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Letter regarding deed from Thomas Fisher, 1795 January 8; [Yi2 1438 F 7] (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Committee of the Trustees of the Loganian Library, 1796 April 28; [Yi2 1438 F 8] (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Trustees of the Loganian Library, 1796 April 15; [Yi2 1438 F 9] (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Library Company of Philadelphia in Trust for the Loganian Library, 1796 June; [Yi2 1438 F 10] (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Library Company of Philadelphia in Trust for the Loganian Library, 1796 August 30; [Yi2 1438 F 11] (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Committee of the Trustees of the Loganian Library, 1796 September; [Yi2 1438 F 12] (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Committee of the Trustees of the Loganian Library, 1796 September 6; [Yi2 1438 F 13] (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Remark on the observation of the Committee of the Loganian Library, 1796 September 14; [Yi2 1438 F 14] (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Reply to Observations of the Executors of William Logan and Statement made by the Committee of the Trustees of the Loganian Library, 1796 November 9; [Yi2 1438 F 15] (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - In the Common Pleas of Philadelphia County: Library Company of Philadelphia v. James Pemberton, et.al., 1797 April 12; [Yi2 1438 F 16] (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Letters from James Gibson and B. R. Morgan to Thomas Fisher, Thomas, 1803 December 1, undated; [Yi2 1438 F 17] (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Committee of the Trustees of the Loganian Library presents their respect to Thomas Fisher, undated; [Yi2 1438 F 18] (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Letter from Thomas Fisher, undated; [Yi2 1438 F 19] (Box 10, Folder 19)